

STEFAN H

infantstefan@gmail.com

+919944669686

CHENNAI, INDIA 600073

Professional Summary

To seek and maintain full-time position that offers professional challenges utilizing interpersonal skills, excellent time management and problem-solving skills. Experienced safety officer with over 4 years of experience in hospital field. Confident Firefighter works effectively as part of cohesive team. Highly trained individual with great mechanical aptitude and background in medical response and fire suppression. Handles issues quickly and resolves conflicts successfully. Communicative Firefighter known for first-rate mechanical aptitude and great integrity. Dependable individual dedicated to enhancing quality of life for citizens and fellow firefighters through productive, safe services. Expertise in providing emergency rescue, performing fire suppression techniques, and maintaining fire apparatus and equipment. Certified in NIST Chennai paired with in-depth knowledge of multiple fire safety programs.

Technical Skills

- Windows 12
- MS Word
- MS Excel
- MS Power Point
- C++

Work History

10/2021 - Current

SAFETY OFFICER & SECURITY OFFICER RAINBOW MEDICARE CHILDRENS HOSPITAL, CHENNAI, INDIA

- Inspected facilities for adherence to fire, hazard and safety guidelines.
- Responded to any emergencies as instructed and with utmost efficiency.
- Recognized, documented and advised on removal of hazards.
- Gathered information, prepared reports, and drafted correspondence related to cases.
- Conducted safety audits and investigated plant quality issues.
- Checked written JSAs and permits for adherence to regulations.
- Developed safety training procedures and authored manuals for distribution to staff members.
- Verified monthly practice of fire drills for every work shift.

- Provided instructions to staffers during fire drills and emergency evacuations.
- Developed safety policies and procedures to be used at medical facilities.
- Identified and eliminated potential safety code deficits and addressed adequacy of fire exits, stairways, aisle spaces and sprinkler systems through annual inspections.
- Carried out day-day-day duties accurately and efficiently.
- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity.
- Inspected worksites, practices and gear for compliance with established safety standards.

07/2017 - 03/2020

SAFETY OFFICER & ASSISTANT SECURITY OFFICER BE WELL HOSPITALS, CHENNAI, INDIA

- Inspected buildings for pre-fire plans, fire hazards and compliance with fire prevention ordinances.
- Trained fire personnel in safe and proper operation and maintenance of fire department apparatus and vehicles.
- Notified fire dispatchers to detail difficulties encountered, request additional firefighters, and obtain emergency supplies.
- Performed maintenance on water tanks, fire hoses and other firefighting equipment.
- Directed evacuations during fires and emergencies to avoid fatalities, injuries, and panic.
- Conducted thorough tests and inspections of gear, equipment, and tools to stay ready for every type of fire.
- Inspected fire and life safety systems and equipment for proper placement at properties.
- Inspected facilities for adherence to fire, hazard and safety guidelines.
- Inspected worksites, practices and gear for compliance with established safety standards.
- Responded to any emergencies as instructed and with utmost efficiency.

01/2016 - 06/2016

SAFETY OFFICER

IND-BHARAT POWER GENCOM LIMITED (IBPGL), TUTICORIN, INDIA

- Inspected worksites, practices, and gear for compliance with established safety standards.
- Inspected facilities for adherence to fire, hazard, and safety guidelines.
- Responded to any emergencies as instructed and with utmost efficiency.
- Recognized, documented, and advised on removal of hazards.
- Conducted safety audits and investigated plant quality issues.

- Helped in managing health and safety programs aligned with industry standards.
- Verified monthly practice of fire drills for every work shift
- Recognized, documented, and advised on removal of hazards
- Developed safety training procedures and authored manuals for distribution to staff members
- Inspected worksites, practices, and gear for compliance with established safety standards
- Checked written JSA and permits for adherence to regulations

Education

05/2019 B.TECH, Mechanical Engineering, Prist Engineering College, CHENNAI

06/2010 **DIPLOMA IN FIRE AND SAFETY ENGINEERING, FIRE AND SAFETY**, **NIFE**, TUTICORIN

05/2009 **DIPLOMA IN ELECTRONICS & COMMUNICATION ENGINEERING**, **Jeyaraj Annapackyam C.S.I Polytechnic College**, TUTICORIN

Certifications

- OCCUPATIONAL SAFETY AND HEALTH TRAINING
- LEVEL 2 IN PRINCIPLES OF RISK ASSESSMENT
- DIPLOMA IN FIRE AND SAFETY ENGINEERING
- IOSH Managing Safely V.5.0
- NEBOSH AWARD IN HEALTH AND SAFETY AT WORK, U.K.
- Fire Watcher Training
- Confined Space Attendant Training
- LEVEL 2 Principles of Fire Safety
- Principles of Risk Assessment
- NDTASNT (MPT, UT, PT, RFT) Level 2

Personal Skills

Flexible and Adaptable

Decision Making

Collaboration

Leadership

Conflict Resolution

Organization and Time Management

Strong communication and

interpersonal skills

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the above-mentioned details are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

If I am given chance, I will do my best to the entire satisfaction of my superior.

Yours faithfully (H.STEFAN)